<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hacking on Sivert Does Stuff Online!</title>
    <link>/series/hacking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hacking on Sivert Does Stuff Online!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>gmail@sivert.pw (Sivert V. Sæther)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>gmail@sivert.pw (Sivert V. Sæther)</webMaster>
    <copyright>GPL-3</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 13:35:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/series/hacking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SkyLabs</title>
      <link>/blog/apprentice/security/skylabs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 13:35:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>gmail@sivert.pw (Sivert V. Sæther)</author>
      <guid>/blog/apprentice/security/skylabs/</guid>
      <description>SkyLabs has surprisingly good stability compared to expectations based on the codebase. I&amp;rsquo;m guessing it&amp;rsquo;s a byproduct of Python that let&amp;rsquo;s us fail pretty safely on almost all endpoints. The in-house development is mainly four services, two JS frontends and two Python Flask backends, all web.
These services are a captive portal, it&amp;rsquo;s API and an admin interface web app and it&amp;rsquo;s API.
We support lots of interesting authentication methods!~</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sircon</title>
      <link>/blog/apprentice/security/sircon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 13:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>gmail@sivert.pw (Sivert V. Sæther)</author>
      <guid>/blog/apprentice/security/sircon/</guid>
      <description>These guys have a few beefy ass physical servers in their own rack in a supposedly EMP and fire safe room in the basement of their offices. Those physical machines run virtual machines that run WHM/cPanel and whatever PHP app the customer would like. But &amp;gt;90% of their customers are non-technical and just only interact with the default WordPress setup and maybe the e-mail service that comes with their cPanel. Most of the people calling in to their support line has problems using their e-mail, and it&amp;rsquo;s usually the end user who fucked up.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security issues</title>
      <link>/blog/apprentice/security/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 13:11:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>gmail@sivert.pw (Sivert V. Sæther)</author>
      <guid>/blog/apprentice/security/</guid>
      <description>Here is a collection of security issues I found, disclosed and got fixed as an apprentice! This one is divided into two main parts corresponding to the company I worked with when finding the issues.
First one is Sircon and second SkyLabs. I have a pretty extensive Non Disclosure Agreement with SkyLabs. So anything I publish to the internet around them needs to be approved or clearly not covered by the NDA.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Duolingo Xp Exploit</title>
      <link>/blog/duolingo-xp-exploit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 22:11:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>gmail@sivert.pw (Sivert V. Sæther)</author>
      <guid>/blog/duolingo-xp-exploit/</guid>
      <description>Your browser does not support the video tag! It&amp;rsquo;s possible for super/pro users to instantly complete speaking only lessons on iOS.
How to reproduce Make sure the Duoling app does not have microphone access. Start a round of &amp;ldquo;Perfect Pronunciation&amp;rdquo; in the &amp;ldquo;Practice Hub&amp;rdquo;. Click continue and when prompted for microphone access, just click cancel. Profit. (Instant perfect lesson!) Summary The bug here seems to be that the first in app prompt for microphone access does nothing, except telling the end user to please give up mic perms.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>