<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>apprentice on Sivert Does Stuff Online!</title><link>https://io.sivert.pw/series/apprentice/</link><description>Recent content in apprentice on Sivert Does Stuff Online!</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><managingEditor>gmail@sivert.pw (Sivert V. Sæther)</managingEditor><webMaster>gmail@sivert.pw (Sivert V. Sæther)</webMaster><copyright>GPL-3</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 09:01:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://io.sivert.pw/series/apprentice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fail2ban</title><link>https://io.sivert.pw/blog/apprentice/fail2ban/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 09:01:03 +0000</pubDate><author>gmail@sivert.pw (Sivert V. Sæther)</author><guid>https://io.sivert.pw/blog/apprentice/fail2ban/</guid><description>At SkyLabs I had the surprisingly pleasant experience of configuring fail2ban for a bunch of production servers. What fail2ban simply does is watch log files, match the lines against predefined regex patterns. After a predefined amount of matches for a specific IP, it gets 🔨 banned. The super cool thing about this is that the max retry, and most options may be set globally, but also locally for each &amp;ldquo;jail&amp;rdquo;. These jails are just configs for the filters.</description></item><item><title>MSAL</title><link>https://io.sivert.pw/blog/apprentice/msal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 14:10:19 +0000</pubDate><author>gmail@sivert.pw (Sivert V. Sæther)</author><guid>https://io.sivert.pw/blog/apprentice/msal/</guid><description>MSAL stands for Microsoft Authentication Library. It&amp;rsquo;s the replacement for ADAL, the Active Directory Authentication Library. Although Microsoft now definitely pushes cloud hard like most tech companies. So MSAL is focused on Azure AD specifically. Where there is a distinct difference between &amp;ldquo;organizational&amp;rdquo; accounts and normal public Microsoft services account.</description></item><item><title>Docker</title><link>https://io.sivert.pw/blog/apprentice/docker/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 17:33:55 +0000</pubDate><author>gmail@sivert.pw (Sivert V. Sæther)</author><guid>https://io.sivert.pw/blog/apprentice/docker/</guid><description>Docker is a super container management system that lets you isolate programs and services. This is very useful, both during development and for production deployment. Because all dependencies may be bundled into the &amp;ldquo;docker image&amp;rdquo;.
And if the program/service is hacked. The adversary will only have access to the container. Which with proper configuration should make it super hard for any adversary to gain persistence.
Local development When using docker for local development.</description></item><item><title>Ansible</title><link>https://io.sivert.pw/blog/apprentice/ansible/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 07:15:24 +0000</pubDate><author>gmail@sivert.pw (Sivert V. Sæther)</author><guid>https://io.sivert.pw/blog/apprentice/ansible/</guid><description>Ansible is a cool tool that lets you manage lots of Linux servers and even some other devices. All with just a bunch of yaml. Although not necessarily as it supports a nice load of formats for everything. Yaml being the most common, but &amp;ldquo;inventories&amp;rdquo; are usually ini format. But still you should be able to do everything in json if you really want to.
Configure ansible.cfg This is the main Ansible config.</description></item><item><title>Azure App Registration</title><link>https://io.sivert.pw/blog/apprentice/azure-app-registration/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 15:05:05 +0000</pubDate><author>gmail@sivert.pw (Sivert V. Sæther)</author><guid>https://io.sivert.pw/blog/apprentice/azure-app-registration/</guid><description>You can find the App Registrations in Azure under Azure AD or directly by search. Once there you can click the &amp;ldquo;New registration&amp;rdquo; button on the top left. Then you&amp;rsquo;ll need to fill in name, account types and optionally a redirect URI.
The Azure App Registration page The first thing to do now is &amp;ldquo;Branding &amp;amp; properties&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip; haha. The app authenticates towards Microsoft with either a certificate or app secrets. So the actual first thing to do is to go over the &amp;ldquo;Authentication&amp;rdquo; tab, just check that all looks good.</description></item><item><title>Handlebars.js</title><link>https://io.sivert.pw/blog/apprentice/handlebars/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 09:14:23 +0000</pubDate><author>gmail@sivert.pw (Sivert V. Sæther)</author><guid>https://io.sivert.pw/blog/apprentice/handlebars/</guid><description>Handlebars.js is a templating engine like jinja2, but entirely in JavaScript.
Personally I&amp;rsquo;ve only found pug templates very nice to work with as I love the minimal syntax.
What makes handlebars cool is it&amp;rsquo;s ability to render templates both server and client side, if you&amp;rsquo;re running node.js on the server.
Running it in the frontend is super easy, check this example from the handlebars docs;
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 &amp;lt;!</description></item><item><title>IT Apprentice</title><link>https://io.sivert.pw/blog/apprentice/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 18:33:08 +0000</pubDate><author>gmail@sivert.pw (Sivert V. Sæther)</author><guid>https://io.sivert.pw/blog/apprentice/</guid><description>This section of my blog serves as an index of technologies I&amp;rsquo;ve learned or became better at as an apprentice working in IT. 😀
It also serves the purpose of the required documentation apprentices in Norway are supposed to do. 😳
Here are lists of stuff I&amp;rsquo;ll be writing about here; ❌ not started 🚧 marks work in progress ✅ marks complete!
Programming Python ❌ Flask 🍼 ❌ SQLAlchemy 🍶 🚧 MSAL (Microsoft Authentication Library) 🪕 Browser JavaScript ❌ jQuery 📲 🚧 Handlebars.</description></item></channel></rss>