<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Security issues on Sivert Does Stuff Online!</title><link>https://io.sivert.pw/blog/apprentice/security/</link><description>Recent content in Security issues on Sivert Does Stuff Online!</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><managingEditor>gmail@sivert.pw (Sivert V. Sæther)</managingEditor><webMaster>gmail@sivert.pw (Sivert V. Sæther)</webMaster><copyright>GPL-3</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 13:11:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://io.sivert.pw/blog/apprentice/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SkyLabs</title><link>https://io.sivert.pw/blog/apprentice/security/skylabs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 13:35:43 +0000</pubDate><author>gmail@sivert.pw (Sivert V. Sæther)</author><guid>https://io.sivert.pw/blog/apprentice/security/skylabs/</guid><description>SkyLabs has surprisingly good stability compared to expectations based on the codebase. I&amp;rsquo;m guessing it&amp;rsquo;s a byproduct of Python that let&amp;rsquo;s us fail pretty safely on almost all endpoints. The in-house development is mainly four services, two JS frontends and two Python Flask backends, all web.
These services are a captive portal, it&amp;rsquo;s API and an admin interface web app and it&amp;rsquo;s API.
We support lots of interesting authentication methods!~</description></item><item><title>Sircon</title><link>https://io.sivert.pw/blog/apprentice/security/sircon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 13:12:00 +0000</pubDate><author>gmail@sivert.pw (Sivert V. Sæther)</author><guid>https://io.sivert.pw/blog/apprentice/security/sircon/</guid><description>These guys have a few beefy ass physical servers in their own rack in a supposedly EMP and fire safe room in the basement of their offices. Those physical machines run virtual machines that run WHM/cPanel and whatever PHP app the customer would like. But &amp;gt;90% of their customers are non-technical and just only interact with the default WordPress setup and maybe the e-mail service that comes with their cPanel. Most of the people calling in to their support line has problems using their e-mail, and it&amp;rsquo;s usually the end user who fucked up.</description></item></channel></rss>