<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>tech on Sivert Does Stuff Online!</title><link>https://io.sivert.pw/tags/tech/</link><description>Recent content in tech on Sivert Does Stuff Online!</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><managingEditor>gmail@sivert.pw (Sivert V. Sæther)</managingEditor><webMaster>gmail@sivert.pw (Sivert V. Sæther)</webMaster><copyright>GPL-3</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 09:01:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://io.sivert.pw/tags/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fail2ban</title><link>https://io.sivert.pw/blog/apprentice/fail2ban/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 09:01:03 +0000</pubDate><author>gmail@sivert.pw (Sivert V. Sæther)</author><guid>https://io.sivert.pw/blog/apprentice/fail2ban/</guid><description>At SkyLabs I had the surprisingly pleasant experience of configuring fail2ban for a bunch of production servers. What fail2ban simply does is watch log files, match the lines against predefined regex patterns. After a predefined amount of matches for a specific IP, it gets 🔨 banned. The super cool thing about this is that the max retry, and most options may be set globally, but also locally for each &amp;ldquo;jail&amp;rdquo;. These jails are just configs for the filters.</description></item><item><title>SkyLabs</title><link>https://io.sivert.pw/blog/apprentice/security/skylabs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 13:35:43 +0000</pubDate><author>gmail@sivert.pw (Sivert V. Sæther)</author><guid>https://io.sivert.pw/blog/apprentice/security/skylabs/</guid><description>SkyLabs has surprisingly good stability compared to expectations based on the codebase. I&amp;rsquo;m guessing it&amp;rsquo;s a byproduct of Python that let&amp;rsquo;s us fail pretty safely on almost all endpoints. The in-house development is mainly four services, two JS frontends and two Python Flask backends, all web.
These services are a captive portal, it&amp;rsquo;s API and an admin interface web app and it&amp;rsquo;s API.
We support lots of interesting authentication methods!~</description></item><item><title>Sircon</title><link>https://io.sivert.pw/blog/apprentice/security/sircon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 13:12:00 +0000</pubDate><author>gmail@sivert.pw (Sivert V. Sæther)</author><guid>https://io.sivert.pw/blog/apprentice/security/sircon/</guid><description>These guys have a few beefy ass physical servers in their own rack in a supposedly EMP and fire safe room in the basement of their offices. Those physical machines run virtual machines that run WHM/cPanel and whatever PHP app the customer would like. But &amp;gt;90% of their customers are non-technical and just only interact with the default WordPress setup and maybe the e-mail service that comes with their cPanel. Most of the people calling in to their support line has problems using their e-mail, and it&amp;rsquo;s usually the end user who fucked up.</description></item><item><title>Security issues</title><link>https://io.sivert.pw/blog/apprentice/security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 13:11:57 +0000</pubDate><author>gmail@sivert.pw (Sivert V. Sæther)</author><guid>https://io.sivert.pw/blog/apprentice/security/</guid><description>Here is a collection of security issues I found, disclosed and got fixed as an apprentice! This one is divided into two main parts corresponding to the company I worked with when finding the issues.
First one is Sircon and second SkyLabs. I have a pretty extensive Non Disclosure Agreement with SkyLabs. So anything I publish to the internet around them needs to be approved or clearly not covered by the NDA.</description></item><item><title>MSAL</title><link>https://io.sivert.pw/blog/apprentice/msal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 14:10:19 +0000</pubDate><author>gmail@sivert.pw (Sivert V. Sæther)</author><guid>https://io.sivert.pw/blog/apprentice/msal/</guid><description>MSAL stands for Microsoft Authentication Library. It&amp;rsquo;s the replacement for ADAL, the Active Directory Authentication Library. Although Microsoft now definitely pushes cloud hard like most tech companies. So MSAL is focused on Azure AD specifically. Where there is a distinct difference between &amp;ldquo;organizational&amp;rdquo; accounts and normal public Microsoft services account.</description></item><item><title>WHM</title><link>https://io.sivert.pw/blog/apprentice/whm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 14:07:06 +0000</pubDate><author>gmail@sivert.pw (Sivert V. Sæther)</author><guid>https://io.sivert.pw/blog/apprentice/whm/</guid><description>WHM/Web Host Manager is the partner/backend admin panel for cPanel. It&amp;rsquo;s made for making shared web hosting super easy. WHM uses a bunch of server software under the hood for managing DNS, e-mails, web-servers and more. With WHM, it&amp;rsquo;s super easy managing a whole-bunch of Apache &amp;ldquo;virtual hosts&amp;rdquo;. One for each cPanel.
WHM also supports having WHM &amp;ldquo;partner&amp;rdquo; accounts out of the box! This means that the company doing shared hosting with WHM may have partners that also have access to the WHM.</description></item><item><title>cPanel</title><link>https://io.sivert.pw/blog/apprentice/cpanel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 14:07:02 +0000</pubDate><author>gmail@sivert.pw (Sivert V. Sæther)</author><guid>https://io.sivert.pw/blog/apprentice/cpanel/</guid><description>I think anyone who uses cPanel should be aware of WHM/Web Host Manager. Although cPanel may run completely on its own, but usually you find its running with WHM. Meaning that whoever sells you the cPanel access sets it up through WHM.
Alone cPanel may be pretty powerful depending on what access you&amp;rsquo;re granted. Often hosting providers will limit you to only access the files of your web-root and settings for additional services like e-mail and DNS.</description></item><item><title>WordPress</title><link>https://io.sivert.pw/blog/apprentice/wordpress/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 14:06:54 +0000</pubDate><author>gmail@sivert.pw (Sivert V. Sæther)</author><guid>https://io.sivert.pw/blog/apprentice/wordpress/</guid><description>WordPress is by far the world&amp;rsquo;s most popular Content Management System. And it makes sense with its ease of use. It&amp;rsquo;s famous for letting anyone have a blog setup within 5 minutes.
For the initial setup you just create an account for the admin panel. And set things like the base URL/domain for the web page.
After that you&amp;rsquo;re free to explore the /wp-admin and make the content for the page.</description></item><item><title>Ansible</title><link>https://io.sivert.pw/blog/apprentice/ansible/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 07:15:24 +0000</pubDate><author>gmail@sivert.pw (Sivert V. Sæther)</author><guid>https://io.sivert.pw/blog/apprentice/ansible/</guid><description>Ansible is a cool tool that lets you manage lots of Linux servers and even some other devices. All with just a bunch of yaml. Although not necessarily as it supports a nice load of formats for everything. Yaml being the most common, but &amp;ldquo;inventories&amp;rdquo; are usually ini format. But still you should be able to do everything in json if you really want to.
Configure ansible.cfg This is the main Ansible config.</description></item><item><title>Matrix, secure and decentralized communications</title><link>https://io.sivert.pw/blog/matrix/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 22:00:52 +0000</pubDate><author>gmail@sivert.pw (Sivert V. Sæther)</author><guid>https://io.sivert.pw/blog/matrix/</guid><description>Matrix is in my opinion super cool. It&amp;rsquo;s a community driven chat system that supports end to end encryption and it&amp;rsquo;s even possible to run it peer to peer if all parties host their own matrix &amp;ldquo;homeserver&amp;rdquo;. There are an absolutely insane amount of these &amp;ldquo;homeservers&amp;rdquo;.
It&amp;rsquo;s recommended you choose one that you trust but any server with the exception of the official matrix.org server should be alright. The official is always under heavy load and will appear even more sluggish than most servers.</description></item></channel></rss>