<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>net on Sivert Does Stuff Online!</title>
    <link>/tags/net/</link>
    <description>Recent content in net on Sivert Does Stuff Online!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>gmail@sivert.pw (Sivert V. Sæther)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>gmail@sivert.pw (Sivert V. Sæther)</webMaster>
    <copyright>GPL-3</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 09:57:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tzsp2pcap</title>
      <link>/blog/apprentice/tzsp2pcap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 09:57:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>gmail@sivert.pw (Sivert V. Sæther)</author>
      <guid>/blog/apprentice/tzsp2pcap/</guid>
      <description>This is a very useful tool when working with Mikrotiks. As their built-in sniffer tool has support for TZSP (TaZmen Sniffer Protocol) streaming. This will send all packets that match the filtering options to some destination over TZSP/UDP.
This destination may be some machine running this tzsp2pcap. Allowing you to get a pcap remotely from a Mikrtoik without touching the Mikrotiks disk. This is super useful if the box has traffic as the Mikrotik routers usually has a disk with a size in megabytes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mikrotik</title>
      <link>/blog/apprentice/mikrotik/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 10:34:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>gmail@sivert.pw (Sivert V. Sæther)</author>
      <guid>/blog/apprentice/mikrotik/</guid>
      <description>Mikrotik produces networking equipment and software. In 2021, they were the 3rd largest and first private company to reach a value above 1B EUR in their home country Latvia.
While their RouterOS has a terrible track record of getting hacked. It has a load of cool and useful features built right in. And all those ROS devices that constantly get hacked do so because of known vulnerabilities that would have been patched if only the devices where being updated on a regular basis.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meraki</title>
      <link>/blog/apprentice/meraki/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 07:14:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>gmail@sivert.pw (Sivert V. Sæther)</author>
      <guid>/blog/apprentice/meraki/</guid>
      <description>Meraki is Cisco&amp;rsquo;s cloud managed networking solution. It has everything and more than what most people would need. But of course me being me, I don&amp;rsquo;t like my infrastructure being managed by cloud services.
I did however work a little with Meraki at SkyLabs, and was pleasantly surprised. After having a couple very bad experiences with our Mikrotik setup script. Setting up a Meraki access point with our captive portal service was super easy!</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>